# Pooja Agarwal, Frontend Developer

Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India 

poojaagarwal367@gmail.com □ (+91)9026343013 ○ github.com/apooja21

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced and motivated Frontend Developer with 2+ years of combined experience in software development, encompassing both testing and frontend development roles. Possesses a strong foundation in core web technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) and modern frameworks (React, Typescript), coupled with backend capabilities in Node.js, MongoDB, and Express.js. Demonstrates adaptability and a passion for learning, evidenced by successful transition from test engineering to frontend development and continuous self-improvement during a career break through freelance projects and skill acquisition in React, Typescript, and backend technologies.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Frontend Developer

Freelance May 2022 - Present

- Developed and maintained responsive user interfaces for various client projects.
- Utilized React, HTML, CSS, and Javascript to build dynamic and interactive web applications.
- · Collaborated with clients to understand their needs and deliver solutions exceeding expectations.

#### **Contract Frontend Developer**

Sijal In Stiches LLP

April 2021 - March 2022

- Created user interfaces with Angular, TypeScript and HTML/CSS to ensure responsive design across platforms, improved web page performance by 25–50%.
- Implemented Primeng Angular UI component library to ensure more efficient usage of the codebase for better and faster development.
- Created landing pages, dashboards for the ecommerce website.
- Collaborated with backend developers to integrate frontend components with back-end APIs.
- Maintained strict budgetary and scheduling guidelines to satisfy customers with high-quality, targeted designs.

## **Test Engineer**

Wipro Limited

November 2018 - November 2020, Bengaluru

- Developed and implemented comprehensive test automation framework, resulting in 20% decrease in test cycles and improved coverage to 60% from 40%.
- Executed various manual and automated tests, and tracked potential software problems via bug tracking system.
- Identified and tracked defects with Jira and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests.
- · Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Created automation scripts using Parasoft SOA Test tool and Jython.
- Kept scripts and test cases updated with current requirements for future reference and use.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java

Frontend: React, Angular, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Backend: MongoDB, NodeJS Others: Figma, Photoshop

#### **PROJECTS**

# Plant Store Website - HTML, CSS

apooja.dev/plant-store-website/

- Designed this website frontend just for fun. It uses HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- It also has Dark and Light theme support.

### **Todo List App - React**

github.com/apooja21/todo-list-app

- Worked on the project for the purpose of learning **React**.
- Built using React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering

Shri Ramswaroop Memorial University, Lucknow · 2014 - 2018 · GPA - 7.38